<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<h2>
Notes:
</h2>
<ul>
<li>When returned in response to a RESTful action, the issue might or might not not be persisted and accessible by its own REST call.
I.e. Issues can be created on the fly and returned without being otherwise accessible.</li> 
</ul>

<h2>Open Issues</h2>
<ul>
<li>It's not clear what, if any, search criteria are needed or appropriate.</li>
<li>Is there a benefit to declaring a base set of detailed issue codes that apply across all types of requests that provide greater detail than HTTP response codes, or 
should the definition of error codes be left to profiles.  (An intermediate step might be to define a code system with a starter set of recommended codes that could be drawn on by profiles.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Relationship with HTTP response codes</h2>
<p>
Issue resources are only relevant when a level of computable detail is required that is more granular than that provided by the HTTP response codes.
This granularity could include:
</p>
<ul>
<li>more detail about the location of an issue</li>
<li>the ability to identify multiple distinct issues</li>
<li>the need to drive automated behavior at a more detailed level than supported by HTTP codes and/or</li>
<li>the need to return information with severities other than "failure"</li>
</ul>
Issue reports returned SHOULD be in alignment with the HTTP response code.  For example, if the HTTP code indicates a failure, at least
one of the issues should have a severity of "error", indicating the reason for the failure.

<h2>Use outside of responses</h2>
<p>
This resource may sometimes be used for purposes other than conveying the results of an attempted action.  Examples include:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Indicating acknowledged issues associated with another resource (e.g. a known drug-drug interaction associated with a prescription)</li>
<li>Identifying possible issues associated with a resource (e.g. as part of a drug formulary)</li>
<li>Pro-actively acknowledging known issues as part of a request so as to allow a desired action to proceed despite the existence of the problem (i.e. as an override)</li>
</ul>
</div>
