<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
Notes:
</p>
<ul>
<li>The Message resource is a special case; it is only defined for the messaging framework, and is not encountered in other contexts</li>
<li>The Message resource is always found in an aggregation. The resource references enterer, author, and responsible may 
  all be included in the aggregation or left out on the basis that the recipient (and any intermediaries) are able to locate/resolve the resources
  independently. The former would be suitable for loosely coupled systems, and the latter for tightly coupled systems. The messaging conformance 
  statement for an application may describe what aggregation occurs or is required here</li>
<li>The actual content of the data is specified per message event. The data resource is always aggregated</li>
</ul>  

<a name="Events"></a>
<h2>Event List</h2>

[%events%]

<a name="mailbox"></a>
<h2>MailBox</h2>
<p>
The mailbox is the standard name for a service hosted on a RESTful server that accepts messages and processes 
them as transactions, and returns a message response appropriate for the message received. The server is under
no obligation to do anything particular with the resources except as required by the semantics of the event code in the 
message resource. A server may choose to retain the resources and make them available on a RESTful interface, but 
is not required to do so. If the server returns 200 Ok, it must return a valid message that indicates what the outcome
of the event processing is. An HTTP error indicates that the message was not processed successfully, and that it should
be resubmitted (and doing so should not result in a duplicate message response).
</p>
<p>
The mail box can also be used to accept documents. In this case, the document is "accepted" (the server 
takes responsibility for custody of the recieved document), and an HTTP status of 204 No Content is returned, 
or an HTTP error is returned. The server is under no obligation to do anything with the document except as 
specific trading partner agreements dictate.
</p>
<p>
The following rules apply to the mailbox:
</p>
<ul>
 <li>The mailbox only accepts POST transactions - any other HTTP method will result in an HTTP error</li>
 <li>The request content type submitted is always an atom aggregation containing a message or document resource as the first resource</li>
 <li>The response content type returned is always an error, an atom aggregation containing a message as the first resource, or empty (if a document was received)</li>
 <li>The URL never takes any parameters</li>
 <li>The mailbox may be authenticated using standard HTTP authentication methods, including OAuth</li>
</ul>
<p>
This simple mailbox profile can be used by any http end point that accepts FHIR messages or documents, not just 
FHIR RESTful servers.
</p>

</div>
