<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
FHIR resources can be used to build clinical documents that capture information about clinical observations and services. 
A clinical document is a bundle (a list of resources in an <a href="atom.htm">atom feed</a>) that is 
fixed in scope, frozen in time and authored and/or attested as a set of logically contained resources by humans, organisations and devices. Documents built in 
this fashion may be exchanged between systems and also persisted in document storage and management 
systems, including systems such as IHE XDS. Applications claiming conformance to this framework claim 
to be conformant to "FHIR documents". 
</p>

<h2>Document Content</h2>
<p>
All documents have the same structure: a <a href="atom.htm">bundle</a> that has a <i>Document
Header</i> resource (below) first, followed by a series of other resources referenced from the Document 
header that provides guidance on how they fit together. The bundle gathers all the content
of the document into a single XML document which may be signed and managed as required. The resources
include both human and computer readable portions.
</p>
<p>
The document header identifies the document and its purpose, sets the context of the document and 
carries key information such as the subject and author. It also divides the document up into a 
series of sections that contain other resources identified in this specification that 
carry the content. Any resource referenced directly in the Document resource must be included
in the bundle when the document is assembled. Other resources that these referenced resources refer to
may also be included in the bundle if the document originator chooses to. 
</p>
<p>
The <i>Document.id</i> identifies the logical document.  Multiple versions of the document 
may exist, each with their own unique bundle identifier (Atom feed.id). The means the <i>Document.id</i>
maps to CDA ClinicalDocument.setId and the <i>feed.id</i> to ClinicalDocument.id.
</p>
<p>
<a href="profile.htm">Document profiles</a> can make additional rules about which resources
must be included in the bundle along with the resources that are directly referenced in the Document resource. 
In addition, Document Profiles can specify what sections a document contains and what the 
constraints on their contents are. Applications should consider publishing <a href="conformance.htm">conformance 
statements</a> that identify particular documents they support.
</p>

<h2>Document End-Points</h2>

<p>There are two RESTful end-points defined for Documents:</p>

<ul>
 <li>[baseurl]/documentheader/: a normal RESTful end point for document header resources</li> 
 <li>[baseurl]/document/: a RESTful end point that serves documents as <a href="atom.htm">bundles</a>. <a href="#rest">This is described below</a></li> 
</ul>
<p>
The first end-point is used for working within the document contents, for instance, for building 
documents piecemeal, for auditing received documents or for providing a document registry. 
The second end-point is used for working with whole documents, such as providing a document 
repository. Servers may un-bundle documents received through the /document/ end-point, 
and make the document resources they contain available through the /documentheader/ end-point, but 
are not required to do so. 
</p>
<p>
RESTful systems may also accept documents through their <a href="messageheader.htm#mailbox">mailbox</a>.
</p>
<p>
Note: While the end-points above are defined for use with document resources and document bundles, 
it is not necessary to use them. Documents may be transferred between systems using any method desired.
</p>
</div>
