<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
There are 4 device related resources
</p>
<ul>
 <li><a href="device.htm">Device</a>  - an administrative resource that tracks individual devices and their location. Primarily used for attribution of actions to devices</li>
 <li>Device Capabilities (this resource) - Defines what observations a device will make when you connect to it directly</li>
 <li><a href="devicelog.htm">Device Log</a> - A raw report from a device at a point in time. Must be paired with the correct Device Capabilities resource in order to be processed</li>
 <li><a href="deviceobservation.htm">Device Observation</a> - A report of observations from a device</li>
</ul>
<p>
The device capabilities and <a href="devicelog.htm">device log</a> resources are used when communicating directly with a device. 
When a channel is opened with the device, it first sends the Capabilities resource, and then a 
series of emission resources. The FHIR JSON format is used in this case. (TODO: What's the communication protocol?)
The application that receives the emission resources may choose to merge the emission with the capabilities 
statement to create a device observation, which is suitable for wider use within a EHR/Clinical record context. 
The Device Capabilites and Device Log resources may be used in a RESTful context, but in many contexts this 
will not be very useful - the data should be converted to a device observation for normal RESTful use in a 
patient care context.
</p>

<p>
Note that this resource is entirely concerned with devices that report data; interacting with an 
controlling devices such as infusion pumps etc is not in scope for this resource. This resource is based on ISO 11073.
</p>

<h3>Structure of the Device Capabilities</h3>

<p>
A medical device is conceived of as a measuring device that is capable of reporting 
a series of groups of measurements on a regular basis. The device capabilities resource 
describes the kind of data that a medical device reports. Devices are conceptualised 
using the following main structure:
</p>
<ol>
 <li><b>Device</b> - The actual device that external systems communicate with</li>
 <li><b>Compartment</b> - (Virtual Medical Device) a medical-related subsystem of a medical device</li>
 <li><b>Channel</b> - groups together physiological measurement data and derived data</li>
 <li><b>Metrics</b> - A piece of measured or derived data that will be reported by the machine</li>
 <li><b>Facets</b> - additional data that qualifies the metric, or contributes to it's assessment</li>
</ol>

<p>
Very simple devices may have only a single compartment with a single channel and one metric, while complex devices may have multiple items at every level. 
</p>
<p>
When the <a href="devicelog.htm">data emitted by the device</a> is converted to a <a href="deviceobservation.htm">Device Observation</a>
based on the information in the capabilities, and known local context, the Metrics level usually corresponds to a 
single <a href="observation.htm">Observation</a>, but this is not appropriate in all cases.
</p>
 
</div>
