<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<!-- insert xhtml content here -->
<a name="status"> </a>
<h2>Item Status</h2>

<p>
Each entry in the list includes a status. The status code can be one of the following values:
</p>
<%codelist ListEntryStatus%>
<p>
The status values are not instructions about what should happen, but a record of what did happen. 
The context of the list must be known in order to understand the meaning of changes to the list. 
For example, if the list concerns current patient medications, then a deleted medication means 
the patient was instructed not to take the medication. 
</p>
<p>
It is not necessary to label an item with a status, however systems must ensure that an
item with no status code is not deleted.
</p>


<a name="status"> </a>
<h2>Narrative Content</h2>

<p>
The narrative portion of the List resource should contain a summary 
of key properties of the items in the list, along with their status 
as indicated in the entry.
</p>
<p>
An HTML table is the recommended approach, though this is not required.
There should be a representation in the narrative for each item in the 
list, and vice versa, along with clear use of visual hints (borders, 
lines, bullet marks, etc) to ensure that human readers do not get 
confused about which status belongs with which item on space-poor displays.
</p>

<a name="status"> </a>
<h2>Empty Reason</h2>

<p>
If the list is empty, there could be several different reasons why this is so. For example:
</p>
<ul>
 <li>There are no appropriate entries for the list (i.e. the patient has no known medications/allergies/history)</li>
 <li>The sender (human or system) deemed that these were not related to this context of patient care (usually for privacy related reasons)</li>
 <li>The source system doesn't support these type of entries</li>
</ul>
<p>
Given these possibilities, and the common and significant first case, source systems SHOULD 
provide an empty reason if the list is empty. Because of the importance of this case, the 
<a href="terminologies.htm#specialvalues">special value "nil known"</a> should be used when 
there are no (significant) entries in this context of care. Note that this concept is 
sometimes described differently, such as "patient denies taking medications", or 
"patient was unable to identify any relevant medical history".
</p>
<p>
When receiving a list, systems should not assume the the list is complete (some entries may 
have been withheld for a variety of reasons), unless there are specific trading partner
arrangements in place, or, if the list is empty, that there are actually nil known, 
unless the "nil known" code is present.
</p>
<p>
If the list is empty, the narrative should contain text equivalent to the empty reason.
</p>

</div>
