<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
FHIR resources can be used to build clinical documents that document clinical observations and services. 
A clinical document is a aggregated collection of resources that is fixed in scope and frozen in time, 
and authored and/or attested as an aggregate by humans, organisations and devices. Documents built in 
this fashion may be exchanged between systems, and also persisted in document storage and management 
systems, including systems such as IHE XDS. Applications claiming conformance to this framework claim 
to be conformant to "FHIR documents". 
</p>

<h2>Document Content</h2>
<p>
All documents have the same structure: an <a href="atom.htm">aggregation</a> that has <i>Document
Header</i> (below) first, followed by a series of other resources referenced from the Document 
header that provides guidance for how they fit together. The aggregation gathers all the content
of the document into a single XML document which maybe signed and managed as required. The resources
nclude both human and computer readable portions.
</p>
<p>
The document header identifies the document and it's purpose, sets the context of the document, and 
carries key information such as the subject and author. It also divides the document up into a 
series of sections that each contain some other resource identified in this specification that 
carries the content. Any resource referenced directly in the Document resource must be included
in the aggregation when the document is assembled; other resources that these documents refer to
may also be aggregated if the document originator chooses to. 
</p>
<p>
<a href="profile.htm">Document profiles</a> can make additional rules about which resources
must be aggregated along with the resources that are directly referenced in the Document resource. 
In addition, Document Profiles can specify what sections a document contains, and what the 
constraints on their contents are. Applications should consider publishing <a href="conformance.htm">conformance 
statements</a> that identify particular documents they support.
</p>
<p>The resource name as it appears in a RESTful URL is /document/. This resource name is for aggregated
documents - <a href="#rest">see below</a> for details.
</p>

</div>
