<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
﻿<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
Notes:
</p>
<ul>
<li>About naming: a laboratory produces "reports" that is a collection of "tests" that produce "results". Clinical consumers call the whole 
collection "the results". There is much potential confusion around these names. The confusion is worsened because "the report" is sometimes a 
document which entirely contains narrative, sometimes it is purely atomic data results, and sometimes it's a mix of both. </li> 
<li>The scope of this resource is the laboratory reporting process. While this resource includes some elements that relate to the ordering cycle, these are only included to the degree that it is useful for the final report to refer back to the orders. Different resources are required for supporting the ordering cycle.</li>
<li>This laboratory report model provides a 3 level structure for the results - a report contains a list of groups, each of which contains a list of results.
Results are grouped by either a specimen or a code that indicates that nature of the grouping (e.g. organism isolate/sensitivity or antibody functional testing). 
While many common lab reports don't need or benefit directly from the group structure, this lab report model imposes the group structure anyway. This means that these 
lab reports have a single group which has no code on it, and which contains all the results. The advantage of this model is that all the results are found 
at the same point in the hierarchy, and there is a single point on the hierarchy - the group - that may influence the meaning of the test.</li>
<li>The element that contains the actual value of the result has a variable name depending on the type. The name is "value" + the type name, ignoring parameters, with a capital on the first letter, e.g. valueInterval or valueString</li>
<li>The clinical information associated with a request can be a simple text summary, or a reference to another resource</li>
<li>The <i>diagnosticTime</i> can be inferred from the specimens, if they are provided, but specimen details are often not provided, and the value of <i>diagnosticTime</i> is always important. The value of the <i>diagnosticTime</i> element must be consistent with the specimen collection times</li>
<li>Applications consuming lab reports must take careful note of updates to lab reports, and particularly note withdrawn reports. 
A report shouldn't be final until all the results are final or amended. If a report is withdrawn, all the results must be 
withdrawn by replacing every result value with the Concept "withdrawn" in the internal terminology <a href="terminologies.htm">"Special values"</a> 
(sid = "http://hl7.org/fhir/sid/fhir/special-values"), and setting the conclusion (if provided) and the text narrative to some text like 
"This report has been withdrawn". A reason may be provided in the narrative. </li>
</ul>
<h3>Relationship between results, narrative, and synoptic reports</h3>
<p>
One difficult aspect of the design of this resource can be captured with a simple question: "just what is a result?" There 
is a wide range of variation in the answers to this question; some respond that a result is inherently measurement based, 
while others focus on the clinical utility of the data item. 
</p>
<p>
Some practical examples:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Tumor dimensions in synoptic reports</li>
<li>Injection volumes in radiology reports</li>
<li>Phenotypes and genotypes in pathology reports</li>
<li>Images (Scatter plots, electrophoresis photos, slide photos, chromatograms)</li>
</ul>
<p>
Which of these are results? For this resource, we have chosen to take an inclusive view; any of these things can be a result, as long 
as they have a formal code or name that has a clinical meaning, and some kind of (possible) value then they can be a result. 
</p>


</div>
</div>
