<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
Notes:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Both Patient and Demographics have an identifier element, and these server different roles: the
Patient.identifier contains zero or more identifiers that are used to identify the patient's record within 
an organisation, while the Demographics.identifier are identifiers that identify the person that is receiving care. Demographics.identifier are normally also used outside the context of healthcare and are often assigned by 
external, possibly national bodies.</li>
<li>The patient may be a person or an animal (in order to support veterinary medicine). Either a person or an animal resource link must be provided, but not both.</li> 
<li>The dietary restrictions are not for specifying medical diets, but for casual dietary restrictions such as vegetarian, diary-free, nut-free, etc.</li>
<li>multipleBirth can be either expressed as a boolean (just indicating whether the patient is part of a multiple birth) or as an integer, indicating the actual birth order.</li>
<li>Patient records may only be in one of two statuses: active (active=true) and retired (active=false). A normal record is active -it is in use. The status retired is used when a record is created as a duplicate or in error. Once the error is discovered, it can either be retired or deleted. A record does not need to be linked to be retired.
</li>
<li>Patient.link is used as an assertion that two or more Patient resources are both about the same actual person. 
If any patient record is linked to another, then the other must be linked back to the source record. 
<font color="Maroon">Ensuring that the links are in agreement across the patient resources in a RESTful contexts 
is the responsibility of the server: it must modify the referenced resources whenever a change the links on any
patient is updated. In a messaging context, patient links SHALL only be updated though the link/unlink events</font>
</li>
</ul>

<h2>Managing Patient Registration</h2>
<p>
Managing Patient registration is a well known difficult problem. Around 2% of registrations are in error, 
mostly duplicate records. Sometimes the duplicate record is caught fairly quickly and retired before much 
data is accumulated. In other cases, substantial amounts of data may accumulate. For these and other 
reasons, the identifiers associated with a patient may change over time.
</p>
<p>
A Patient record's Resoure Id can never change. For this reason the identifiers with 
which humans are concerned (often called MRN - Medical Record Number, or UR - Unit Record) should not 
be used for the resource' id. Instead they should be represented in the <i>Patient.identifier</i> 
list where they can be managed. This is also useful for the case of institutions that have acquired 
multiple numbers because of mergers of patient record systems over time.
</p>
<p>
This specification does not specify merge functionality: if multiple patient records are found to be 
duplicates, this can be assserted using Patient.link. Fhir servers MAY additionally provide functionality to merge one or more Patient resources and copy or reassign related information to a single (new) Patient resource, but are not required to do so.
</p>
<p>
When patient resources are linked, one may be chosen as the "master" - the correct record. In this case, the active status of all the other resources is set to false, and all the content is moved to the active record by updating
it directly. 
</p>
<h2>Linking using Batch</h2>
<p>
Linking records is effectively a transaction that involves at least two resources, and all or none must change. To effectuate this transaction in a RESTful context, it must be implemented as a <a href="http.htm#transaction">transaction</a> operation.
</p>

</div>
