<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/xhtml1-strict.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
Notes:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Links: linking patient records is an assertion that they both are about the same actual person. If any
 patient record is linked to another, then the other must be linked back to the source record. 
 <font color="Maroon">Ensuring that the links are in agreement across the patient resources in a RESTful contexts is the 
   responsibility of the server: it must modify the referenced resources whenever a change the links on any patient is updated. In a messaging context, patient 
   links SHALL only be updated though the link/unlink events</font></li>
<li>The patient may be a person or an animal (in order to support veterinary medicine). Either a person or an animal resource link must be provided, but not both.</li> 
<li>The dietary restrictions are not for specifying medical diets, but for casual dietary restrictions such as vegetarian, diary-free, nut-free, etc.</li>
<li>multipleBirth can be either expressed as a boolean (just indicating whether the patient is part of a multiple birth) or as an integer, indicating the actual birth order.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Managing Patient Registration</h2>
<p>
Managing Patient registration is a well known difficult problem. Around 2% of registrations are in error, 
mostly duplicate records. Sometimes the duplicate record is caught fairly quickly and retired before much 
data is accumulated. In other cases, substantial amounts of data may accumulate. For these and other 
reasons, the identifiers associated with a patient may change over time.
</p>
<p>
The master identifier for the Patient Resource can never change. For this reason the identifiers with 
which humans are concerned (often called MRN - Medical Record Number, or UR - Unit Record) should not 
be used as the master identifier. Instead they should be represented in the <i>Patient.identifier</i> 
list where they can be managed. This is also useful for the case of institutions that have acquired 
multiple numbers because of mergers of patient record systems over time.
</p>
<p>
In this specification, patient records are never merged. If multiple patient records are found to be 
duplicates, they are linked. In a RESTful context, this is done using the "link patients" transaction
described below. In other contexts, equivalent functionality will be needed. When patient resources 
are linked, one may be chosen as the "master" - the correct record. In this case, the active status 
of all the other resources is set to false, and all the content is moved to the active record by updating
it directly. 
</p>
<p>
Patient records may only be in one of two statuses: active and retired. A normal record is active 
- it is in use. The status retired is used when a record is created in error. Once the error is 
discovered, it can either be retired or deleted. A record does not need to be linked to be retired.
</p>
<h2>RESTful Transactions</h2>
<p>
The patient resource type defines one special transaction provided by the patient manager: "Link" for 
linking resources. The reason is that linking records is effectively a transaction that involves at 
least two resources, and all or none must change. Since the transaction involves multiple resources, 
it is implemented on the resource manager as a POST to [todo]
</p>
<p>
There is no content model for the response, except for an HTTP status code.
</p>


</div>
